Ryan Wang

ryanwang@cmail.carleton.ca | 613-4156006 | ON, CA | trainkin.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-wang-280322103/ System Engineer, Software Developer, Solution Consultant

Summary

An innovative thinker professional with software engineering. Offering more than 6 yrs of working experience in the full software development lifecycle - from concept through delivery of applications and solutions. Experience in design, analysis, implementation, and architecture. Willing to take ownership of core components.

Skills & Endorsements

Software Development, Server Architecture, Web/Mobile Applications, Search Engine, Security Assurance, Agile Project Management, Performance and scalability optimization, Database design, Data warehousing and analytics.

- Programming Languages: Python, C, Java, C++, JavaScript, HTML5, Go, Ruby, SQL, NoSQL, Racket, Prolog, Clojure, C#, Swift.
- Database: MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Memcached, HBase,
- Platform & Tools: RAD & Websphere, Eclipse & IntelliJ IDEA, AngularJS & Bootstrap,
 Android&IOS, Hadoop, Git, Vim, Elasticsearch & ELK, Atlassian Bamboo, Openshift & Docker,
 Maven & Spring-boot, Google Cloud Platform & AWS, Tornado, Django, Flask, Google Map, Nginx,
 Qt, Android Studio, Xcode, Visual Studio, OpenCV, LaTex, Tensor Flow, Ruby on Rails.

Experience

Senior Developer Specialist (Contractor) | BMO | Toronto | Dates 2018.8 – current

BMO Log Enhancement Project, enhance BMO Online Banking logs, security issues, integrate correlation ID to downstream services. ELK (Elasticsearch Logstash Kibana)

Software Developer | dawn infotek inc | Toronto | Dates 2018.6 – current

Responsible for ELK, frontend development (AngularJs 6). Analyzed BMO logs.

Software Developer | T24 defence | Ottawa | Dates 2017.9 – 2018.6

Participated in message transfer through T24 device to monitor, including sensors (track24, whisper, T24 pocket) and satellite (iridium). Built automated front end testing, implemented simulator.

Server Development Engineer | Shou | Beijing | Dates 2015.7 – 2015.9

Worked with team to enhance and improve company product - ShouTV, archived online payment process (google play, apple pay), programming logic optimization. Designed Database structure and REST APIs for client-side (IOS, Android).

Server Development Engineer | Adesk] | Beijing | Dates 2013.10 – 2015.3

Responsible for building and maintaining backend services for company product - android wallpaper. Built REST API (With python + tornado + MongoDB + Redis + Memcached) for client-side's request (IOS, Android). Developed efficient search functions (using elasticsearch).

As a member of data analysis team, I initialized Hadoop for big data storage and built analysis programs for

the department of commercial market. Managed cluster storage and servers status (Nagios). Leading project: Android-ringing: android ringing application is a mobile ringing service to android users. As the leader of the project, my role was to lead our small team to build the server side of the project including backend (with python + tornado) and frontend (html5 + bootstrap CSS + js).

Software Engineer | TRS | Beijing | Dates 2012.1 - 2013.6

Developed and maintained search engine, web spider, proxy servers. Responsible for distributed heavy tasks, built tools for certified users, batch task generating program, multi-threaded web server & associated tools.

In panda project (government project): provided government private web spider and search engine.

Technical Service Engineer | <u>Tsinghua Tongfang</u> | Beijing | Dates 2011.5 – 2012.1 Troubleshooting for PC users: handled software installation and configuration, built script for cluster servers;

Windows System Configuration: built Exchange 2010, Lync, SCCM, CRM; Linux System Configuration: built KVM, XEN, LAMP, postfix, BIND, DHCP, etc.

Education

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science, Carleton University, Canada 2015-2017

University of Ottawa 2016 Bachelor's Degree, Telecommunications Engineering, Hunan University of Arts and Science, China 2007-2011

Certifications

MCITP Microsoft, License D238-2597 Starting April 2011 *CCNA* Cisco, License CSCO 11809486 July 2010 – July 2013

Interests

Web & Mobile application | Machine Learning | Computer Vision | Cryptocurrency | Real Time OS | Gaming | Big Data analysis | Algorithms | Math | Machine Translate | Voice Recognition | Computational Linguistics